We started work in the same year,
当年我们 一起入行
as if we were standing
就好像站在
on the same starting line.
同一条起跑线上
When the starting pistol shot,
发令枪 砰的一声响
everyone started
大家一起开始
a long-running race.
一场长跑比赛
The financial industry
但是金融行业啊
needs us to keep high intensity,
要保持一个 高强度
which is so tiring.
实在太累了
We could bear it in our twenties,
二十多岁身体还吃得消
but 35-year-old is a hurdle,
三十五岁那就是个坎
when many people
很多人呢
can't bear the intensity
扛不住
with their passion wearing away.
热情消磨掉了
So, they leave and change the industry.
就离开了 就转行了
As for me,
我呢
I have been buried myself
倒是一直埋头在
in endless running.
跑啊跑啊跑啊跑
As a result,
结果呢
looking back,
一回身一看
I have fewer partners left.
身边的伙伴 越来越少
And I quit in the middle of the race.
那我也是中途退场的啊
You didn't quit
你不是因为
because of the enthusiasm
扛不住热情消磨掉
wearing away,
而退场的
but you were having
你是进行了一场
long halftime.
漫长的中场休息
Your race was interrupted
你的比赛是因为你
artificially through
结婚生孩子
marriage and child-rearing.
被人为打断了
So, your passion for the profession
但你对这个职业的热情
does not wear away,
非但没有消磨
but becomes stronger
反而因为你的离开
as you left.
而与日俱增
Do you think I make sense?
你说我说得对不对
Yes.
对
I'm now indeed passionate.
我现在确实热情高涨
I think every day now
我就觉得每一天
is a lucky day.
是赚来的
I don't feel toilsome,
我不觉得辛苦
nor do I feel tired.
也不觉得累
The boss likes employees
老板就喜欢你这种
who don't feel toilsome
不觉得辛苦
or tired, as you are.
不觉得累的员工
Come on!
加油
Earn more money, and run forward!
给我挣钱 往前跑
Wish I could catch up with you!
希望能追得上你啊
Of course, you can.
你一定追得上
Maybe one day,
没准哪天
you'll be my boss.
你成为我老板呢
How come?
怎么可能
You are my boss.
你是我老板
I'll do anything
你指到哪儿
at your commands.
我打到哪儿
Brilliant! We work together again!
真好 我们又在一起了
I can recall
想当年
when we were
咱们在同一个组
working for the same boss,
向同一个老板汇报
you were always on top of me.
但你总压我一头
The past has gone.
以前的事了
Stop mentioning it!
别提了好吗
I insist.
必须提
You are the only one
我不跟你提
I can mention the story.
我跟谁提啊
Okay, go on.
好 你说 你说 你说
I'll never mention it to anyone else.
我跟任何人都不会提的
Every athlete
就跟运动员
has one's competitor.
都有一个克星一样
And you're my competitor.
你就是我的克星
I could win everyone in the company,
我可以赢公司所有人
except for you.
但我就是赢不了你
No wonder when I resigned,
怪不得我离职的时候
you gave me
你送了我一个
a luxury bag.
特别贵的包
It was not a big deal.
送个包算什么呀
Let me tell you a secret.
我跟你说个秘密啊
When I heard you resigned,
你当时因为怀孕离职
I breathed a sigh of relief
我当时心里面
in my heart.
大大地松了一口气
I know I was very low back then.
我都觉得我那时候很俗
I felt so relieved
我很庆幸
that I'd like to celebrate.
我真的想庆祝一下
Let alone the bag,
别说送你包了
I wanted to buy you any luxury!
送再贵的都行
Luckily, I am a man.
我庆幸我是个男的
My career won't be affected
我不会因为什么结婚啊
by marriage,
生孩子啊
or child-rearing.
影响事业
Since then,
从那之后呢
I've gone through
我就一路的
promotion,
升职
and entrepreneurship
创业
in a smooth way.
就非常地顺利
I myself know clearly
但我自己知道
the beginning of my success
这一切的起点
originates from your resignation.
就源于你的离开
I see,
原来
so I was the devil haunting you.
我是你心里的那个魔
I...
我
am not anymore.
现在不行了
I've left for seven years.
我现在都离职七年了
I can never become
不可能成为谁
anyone's devil anymore.
心中的那个魔
Wanzhen,
婉真
don't repeat
别老把离开
the halftime endlessly.
职场七年挂在嘴边
Most of the working women
职场女性啊
are too modest
大多数都是
but lack of confidence.
谦虚有余而自信不足
You must have great confidence
但做投资人这行
to be a professional investor.
一定需要强大的自信
Only with great confidence
你只有强大的自信
can you determinedly
你才会无比坚定地
trust your judgment.
相信自己的判断
Seven years is not long.
七年算什么
Every step in life counts.
人生没有白走的路
I am sure
我相信你在
you will remake achievements
投资这一行里面
in the investment industry,
一定会重新做出成绩
and even better.
而且会越做越好
Can I?
我可以吗
Of course, you can.
你当然可以
Thanks for your inspiration.
谢谢周总的鼓励
You know what?
你知道吗
Your encouragement
你的鼓励
is more precious than gold.
比金子还珍贵
Okay.
行啊
I'll encourage you every day.
那我以后每天都说一点
An,
安安
what should I do?
你说我怎么办
I didn't mean to be unreasonable,
真的不是我矫情
but I don't know
我真的不知道
what to do now.
该怎么办了
Your dad fell down
你爸昨天就在那
on the treadmill
康复机上
accidentally,
不小心摔了一下
so, he refuses rehabilitation training,
他今天他就不练了
nor does he eat anything!
饭也不吃
I criticized him a little bit,
我 我就说了他几句嘛
and he threw his temper at me,
他就跟我发那么大脾气
and spoke demoralizing words,
还净说些丧气话
like,
说
his lifetime
说他的命数
will end these days!
就到此为止了
My dad is ill.
我爸 生病了嘛
It is inevitable
那心情不好
to lose his temper.
发发脾气难免的
I hope you can tolerate him.
你多理解理解
Think about it.
那你想
How well did he treat you before?
他以前对你多好啊
Right?
是不是
Yeah.
是
I know. I understand him.
我知道 我理解你爸
I'm afraid he said it
他是怕他以后
because he'll be
照顾不了我了
my burden
拖累我
without looking after me.
给我添麻烦
Since I married your dad,
我从结婚跟你爸在一起
your dad
你爸
hasn't allowed me to do housework.
就让我不做家务做仙女
I've been enjoying life
我这仙女
for decades,
都做了几十年了
and I can do nothing!
我啥也不会
Seriously ill as he is,
他现在这样
how can I leave him alone?
我怎么能不管他呀
How about learning
我 我就从头
from scratch?
我学
I can learn everything.
我什么都学
Although sometimes,
虽然有时候
I may forget something,
可能会忘了些事
but,
但是
I've tried my best!
我真的尽力了
I know you have.
尽力了 尽力了
He can't
那他不能
treat me like that!
这么跟我耍横啊
If he's seeking death,
你说他不活了
what should we do?
我们怎么办哪
I'm sorry to hear that.
委屈了 委屈了
So sorry!
我妈委屈了
There, there.
好了 好了 好了
Don't cry!
不哭了 不哭了啊
Be good.
不哭了 乖啊
I'll try to persuade him.
一会儿我去说他去
There, there.
好了 好了
Don't cry.
不哭了啊
We still need to keep our elegance,
咱 咱还当仙女呢
right?
好不好
You heard that,
你老伴在外边说的话
didn't you?
你都听见了吧
I know you're awake.
我知道你没睡
What are you thinking about?
那你是想怎么的呀
Are you eating
你是就今天
nothing today,
这一顿不吃啊
or nothing forever?
还是以后都不吃了呀
If you choose the latter,
你要是以后都不吃了
I'll prepare for the funeral
那我就给你准备准备
for you.
后边的事
Why are you staring at me?
你瞪我干吗呀
I'm telling the truth!
我实事求是嘛
Your wife
那 你们家仙女
is crying
在外边哭得
sadly outside,
一把鼻涕一把泪的
and it's not my fault.
我哄不了
Shouldn't you take the duty
你自己这辈子咋惯的
for indulging her?
你心里没数啊
You take care of it!
那谁能接得住啊
If you abandon all of us,
你说你要是走了的话
she
你们家仙女
may also leave us with you.
是不是就跟着去了
Eat!
吃
Eat?
吃啊
No death!
把我说死了
If no eat,
不吃
our paths may end together.
把你也说死了
Then eat now.
那赶紧吃
Come on.
来来来 快
Let's eat!
来来 吃啊 咱吃
Bad girl!
不孝
Bad guy!
坏老头
So exhausted!
身心俱疲
What is a straight-A student?
学霸是什么
A straight-A student
学霸就是相同的内容
would review
多学几遍
for several times.
才是学霸
You're bound to forget
你光上课跟着学
by learning once in class.
那学一遍就忘记了呀
If the foundation
这个基础知识
is unstable,
不扎牢的话
one can never draw inferences.
那怎么举一反三呀
Students are working too hard
孩子现在啊 很辛苦的
to have time to play.
没时间玩的
If you let him
你让他每天啊
only think about
想着这些
drills and exams,
复习题呀 考试题呀
he can't be happy.
他也不会快乐的
Do you really believe
你以为玩就是一个
happy childhood is of playing?
快乐的童年呀
Let me tell you.
我跟你说吧
Children
孩子们啊
like it
都是喜欢
to be disciplined by parents,
爸爸妈妈管着的
as long as it's
只要你注意一下
in a proper way.
这个管理的方法
Children
孩子们啊
desire for their parents' support,
都希望父母托举的
so that
可以成为
they can be a better self.
更优秀的自己呀
They came out!
出来了 出来了
Here!
来了
Dad!
老爸
Lulu!
璐璐
Let's go!
走走走
you must be tired.
累了吧
How's study today?
今天怎么样 过得
Pretty good.
挺好的
We're leaving now. Bye-bye.
走了 拜拜
Okay. Goodbye.
好 再见 再见
Goodbye.
再见 再见
We're here!
这儿 这儿 这儿
Where's your mom?
你妈呢
How's it going?
怎么样
Is Xin okay?
心心 怎么样了
Pretty good.
挺好的
The wound heals well.
伤口 愈合得不错
She didn't answer my phone.
给她打电话也不接
You deserve it!
活该
I wouldn't either if I were her.
换我我也不接
Nobody in a bad temper would answer it.
气头上呢 能接吗
Forget it.
行了行了
Don't overthink.
你也别想多了
She's throwing a tantrum.
就是撒个娇
But the way is different.
那以前撒娇也没这样啊
Well, who asked you to annoy her?
谁让你给她一刀的
No.
不
Stop talking nonsense.
你就别跟我刀刀刀了
Did I do it deliberately?
那是我给她一刀吗
She had no choice!
她不刀行吗
As a mom, you should know it.
你这又不是没生过孩子
She knows everything.
所以啊 她什么都懂的
So, how can we
那你说我们俩
comfort her?
这现在 怎么弄啊
That's easy.
还能怎么弄啊
Give her an out.
找个台阶下呗
Lower your profile.
装孙子会吧
That's your strength.
这可是你的强项啊
It's tiring to do so, okay?
装孙子也很累的 好吧
Well,
你
how are you recently?
你现在怎么样啊
Are you doing okay?
精力 体力 跟得上吗
Carrying a baby at my age
这个年纪生孩子
cannot compare to that in my twenties.
真的跟二十多岁没法比
The energy is deficit.
体力 精力 真的是
But it's also an edge.
不过也挺好
My professional life
反正我现在在工作上
has reached its peak.
也不可能更进一步了
Without performance,
没有业绩呢
everyone can understand
大家也会觉得
that a pregnant woman
她是个孕妇
can be forgiven.
放过她吧
During the transition,
我就平稳过渡
I feel fine.
挺好
It seems that
看来二胎
the baby is your excuse.
是你的保命符啊
Pretty good.
挺好的
Do you want more babies?
要不要你也来一个
How's your relationship
那个小医生
with the young doctor?
怎么样了
You're acting like
你看看你那个
a gossip girl!
八卦的表情
Well,
不是
it's so normal!
那很正常嘛
I think it's normal
谁八卦
to be gossiping!
不是我这种表情啊
Let me tell you.
我跟你说啊
Have less milk tea
这个奶茶啊 蛋糕啊
and cakes.
少吃一点
We should put weight management
身材和这个体重管理
on the agenda.
还是要提上日程的
We'll welcome our second wind
我们要用完美的自己
in a perfect
迎接自己第二春的
posture.
到来
I don't believe
你们公司人说你
that you're not
精力跟不上
energetic anymore.
那都是眼瞎
Spill the tea. Come on.
说嘛 快点
What? No comment.
说啥 没有
Nothing.
没有
I smell a rat.
这是 有戏呀
No, really!
真的没戏
I'm already disturbed
现在于海已经把我
by Yu Hai,
搞得很烦躁了
and I don't need another man!
你就别跟我提他了
Alright?
行吗
Yu...
于 于
Does Yu Hai
于海
want to remarry you?
是 想跟你复婚吗
Nice try!
想得美
To be honest,
说实话
what on earth
你觉得于海这个人
do you think of him?
到底怎么样啊
Yu Hai is not a playboy.
于海这个人吧 人不坏
Living with him for so many years,
跟他这么多年一起
I admit we used to love each other.
你说没感情那是假的
After all,
他毕竟嘛
he's the father of two kids.
是两个孩子的爸爸
That relationship
这种关系
cannot ever be given up.
是没有办法割舍的
Most importantly,
最重要的是
I just got into the investment bank,
我刚刚到投行呢
so, I don't want affairs
我不想搞这些
to disturb me,
乱七八糟的事
but devote myself to work.
我就想一心搞事业
So, he's passed.
就是又被刷掉了呗
Any handsome
那在投行呢
in the investment bank?
有看顺眼的吗
Or,
或者
does anybody like you?
有没有谁喜欢你呀
Jesus!
我天哪
Are you the leader of a gossip club?
你是不是八卦精变的呀
Yes, I am.
是 我承认
Spill the tea.
说吧 来
What?
说什么呀
Does anybody like you?
有没有人喜欢你呀
Like, the boss, your colleague,
什么老板哪 同事啊
and... your employee!
还有什么 员工
The boss of the company
我们现在公司的老板呢
is my old colleague.
是我的老同事
At work,
那 在工作上
he cares about me.
还是蛮照顾我的啊
Only at work?
就工作上照顾吗
How about at life?
生活上没点关怀
Yes!
有
No!
没有
He likes joking!
他就是爱开玩笑而已
No.
不
We're mature enough.
我们都是成年人了
We know where the bottom line is.
这个分寸感还是有的
Yu Hai is still your priority.
那就还是于海优先了呗
Let him try even harder!
那得让他加把劲啊
Could you please stop mentioning him?
你能不能不提他了啊
Okay, I won't.
不提 不提 不提
I'm pretty worried about you.
我倒是挺担心你的啊
If you keep gossiping,
天天聊八卦
aren't you afraid
你那小孩出来 你说
your baby
这胎教
will be like you?
怎么弄啊
Don't worry.
放心
Li Lin and I
我跟李临聊的
used to have a
比跟你聊的
much deeper conversation.
深入多了
My Gosh!
天哪
You beat me.
服了
When
王哲
Wang Zhe was at home alone,
在家里一个人的时候
he would inspire himself
自己激励自己
to rank the first.
就想得第一
He would cry if he ranked second.
得个第二又还要哭
Really?
真的假的
Is he happy to push himself?
这王哲这样 他快乐吗
I don't think so.
我觉得不快乐
He's annoyed with his mother.
王哲都很烦他妈
However,
不过呢
Wang Zhe is an
王哲就属于那种
inborn straight-A student.
天生的学霸
He loves drills and study,
他就爱做题 就爱学习
with no other hobbies.
没有别的爱好
I didn't know he was like that.
他是这样的孩子啊
His mother asked me
他妈妈还说了
to ask your mother
说让我去问问你妈妈
if
是
it's happy to play or to succeed.
玩快乐 还是成功快乐
Do you even bother to ask?
这还用问吗
Feisty as my mom is,
对于我妈那种卷王来说
she loves the happiness of success.
她肯定喜欢向上的快乐
Your mom is not wrong.
但是你妈妈说得没错
It depends on the perspective.
看怎么理解了
Pursuing success is a positive attitude,
向上 是积极的态度
while happiness
快乐呢
is an impetus,
是动力
a state of mind.
是一种状态
Dad,
爸
I recall you told me once
我记得你之前跟我说过
when you were young,
你小的时候就
you loved doing homework,
特别爱写作业
just like Wang Zhe did.
就像王哲那样
Were you happy?
你快乐吗
I was happy.
我快乐啊
I was very happy.
真的 我很快乐
When I tackled a difficult problem,
当一道难题被我攻克了
I felt so joyful.
我就觉得我很开心
to have a sense of achievement.
我觉得我有种 成就感
And I was craving
我就想着
for more difficult ones.
有没有更难的题
Of course,
当然了
I think
我觉得
one is different from another.
人和人是不一样的
I won't
我也不会
request you in my standard.
拿这个来要求你
All I wish is that you are happier
我就希望你比我小时候
than I was.
更快乐
I'm very happy now.
我现在就很快乐啦
I can hang out with my besties,
我可以跟我闺蜜去玩
travel with you and mom,
还可以跟你们去旅游
eat all kinds of delicious food,
吃好多我想吃的好吃的
listen to my favorite music,
听我喜欢的音乐
play the piano, and go to the concert!
弹琴 看演唱会
But,
可能
there's no chance for me to be
注定成为不了
a straight-A student like Wang Zhe.
像王哲那样的学霸了吧
You don't need to be others.
你不需要像谁
I don't need you
我也不需要你
to be like others.
像别人孩子一样
You just get on your own way,
你就按照你自己的想法
to grow up
成为你想
into someone you want to be.
成为的人去成长
And that's my ideal
这才是我理想中的
daughter.
女儿
Why don't you get it straight?
你就直说呗
I am an ordinary kid
我就是那种
who is easily distracted,
精力分散的普娃
but not a talent.
不是别人家的牛娃
No, no.
不不不
I'm not laughing at you.
我不是在调侃你啊
I mean it, seriously.
我说真的
Knowing your thoughts,
你这么想
I feel so relieved.
我很安心
It proves that
说明你
you have a good mental state.
心态很好
Healthy mindset.
很健康啊
Anyway,
但是话说回来啊
if you're in,
你要玩
give it your all,
你就认认真真地玩
and study
要学习
as hard as you can.
咱们就努力地学习
That's how a happy life works.
思路一定要清晰
Understood?
明白吗
Yes, I do.
明白了
My daughter has grown up.
我闺女长大了
A hint is all that is needed.
一说就明白
I'll try my best!
我要努力
Yes!
对
To play as hard as I can!
我要努力地玩
Haven't I
我是不是哪里
made it clear?
没有说明白
I'm kidding.
我逗你的
I know what you mean!
我都明白了
Naughty!
逗我
Let's eat fried chicken!
吃炸鸡去
Yes!
好
I'm kidding.
我逗你的
Let's go for fried chicken!
走吧 炸鸡去吧
Catch me!
抓我
Catch the last one!
抓最后一个
I'm coming!
抓 来了 来了
Wanwan.
婉婉
Mom!
妈妈
Allow us to play a little longer!
你再让我们玩一会儿
Okay. Go ahead.
行 玩吧 玩吧
Accompany them for a while.
你陪她们玩一会儿
Okay.
行
Off duty, Ms. Chen?
下班啦 陈小姐
You're having a good time
看你跟孩子
with these children!
还玩得挺好啊
I'm good at it.
我擅长这事嘛
I noticed you put
我看阳台上面
a male jacket on your balcony.
放了件男士外套
You saw it?
你看到了
Your advice is great.
你的建议很好
So, I took your good advice.
所以呢 我从善如流
Let's play together.
一起玩会儿
Okay.
好
Play with us!
行 快 陪我们一起玩
Alright!
好嘞 好嘞
Mom will play with you!
妈妈陪你们一块儿玩
Come here.
来来
I also want this!
我也要这个
I want this!
我想要这个
Okay.
好
The petrol milk.
汽油牛奶
We are big cars,
我们是大汽车
so, we should drink petrol milk.
所以我们要喝汽油牛奶
The above is my newly made
以上就是我新做的
creative product solution
我们新媒体
of our new media.
创意产品方案
The Internet evolves so fast
互联网飞速迭代
that the product three months ago
三个月前的产品
has been phased out.
已经不适应当下了
After reviewing
我希望大家看完
the plan,
这个方案以后
you're expected to find
能够为咱们新苗
a new direction of products
找到新的产品方向
and dynamic for Xinmiao.
还有活力
I think highly of the plan
我看这个思思方案
made by Sisi.
提得非常好
Her idea goes along with
也迎合了现在
the market development needs.
市场发展的需求
We can put it into practice now.
我觉得可以上马 干
I used to raise the project
这个项目我之前
to you before,
跟您提过的
but you denied it.
您不同意上的
Have you?
提过吗
Recently,
最近一次
when you got your house ownership.
是你拿房产证那天
Yeah, I recalled it.
想起来了 想起来了
The company was in a slump then.
那时候公司不是不好吗
But now it has recovered.
你现在缓过来了
Besides,
你再有
how wonderful it is that you two
总监和副总监想法一致
have the same idea!
是不是 这多好
Carry it out right away.
那就上马吧
About
那关于
personnel
人员
and funds,
还有经费
What's on your mind about this?
黄总监是怎么考量的呢
Don't worry.
放心
I need no extra help.
我不用追加人手
I can use the least budget
我肯定用最少的预算
and the lowest personnel cost
和最低的人员成本
to have it done.
把事情搞好
If I have to spend a lot
如果非要拼命砸资源
in finishing the task,
才能把事情做完
what are you hiring me for?
找我来干吗
Mu,
阿木
see the difference?
看到差距了吗
Let's congratulate the project team
恭喜项目组
on getting the order of Aiying!
我们成功地拿下了爱婴
We laid out the mother-and-baby track,
我们布局了母婴赛道
and helped the leader of the industry
帮行业的老大
expand and consolidate its share,
扩大巩固了行业份额
which is a win-win cooperation!
这是双赢的好事情
Tonight, it's my treat.
今天晚上 我做东
All team members will
请项目组所有成员
have a drink!
喝一杯
The person we should
但这个项目呢
be grateful most
最应该感谢的人
is Wendy.
就是温蒂
Wendy, without you,
温蒂 没有你
we wouldn't have reached Mrs. Wei,
就拿不下爱婴的魏总
nor would we have
我们也就不会
signed a contract.
成功地签约
It's my duty.
这是我应该做的
I feel so lucky.
其实我挺幸运的
Both Mrs. Wei and I
因为我跟魏总呢
are mothers of two kids,
都是两个孩子的母亲
so, we talk in the same language.
所以有共同话题
It's not because you're lucky,
这不是你的幸运
but it's your strength.
这是你的实力
You're not only
你不仅是
a mother of two kids,
两个孩子的母亲
but also an excellent
你还是个优秀的
working woman.
职场女性
If I have to spend a lot
要是做什么
in finishing the task,
都用资源砸的话
what are you hiring me for?
还招我干吗呢
Is that what she said?
她真这么说呀
How ambitious she is!
够狂的呀
But she also makes sense.
人家说得也在理的
I'm just a little bit angry
我主要是有点气不过
because her project
就她现在弄的这个项目
has been mentioned to Mr. Zhang
我之前跟老张
for many times.
提过好多次
He never accepted it.
老张死活不做
When Huang Sisi came,
结果黄思思一来
he instantly initiated it.
他就启动了
He explained to me that
还美其名曰说什么
since everyone likes it,
既然大家都很看好
it is worth carrying out.
那就说明值得做
Aren't you angry with it?
你说气人不气人
You should understand him.
你也得理解
As a new Deputy Director,
本来黄思思这种空降兵
she's in a weak position.
就容易水土不服
She's also hired by Mr. Zhang
老张又是自己从外面
with a high salary.
高薪把人给挖过来
It's reasonable for him to support her,
那肯定得扶持呀
or her value won't stand out.
要不然怎么体现价值呀
If her value can't stand out,
体现不出价值
it means he chose the wrong person,
那他不就白挖了吗
right?
对吧
Maybe Mr. Zhang gives her
估计老张是想
a chance to show off,
扶上马 送一程
and see if he can help her
就看他扶不扶得起来
make a success.
这一把了
However,
但是啊
if he succeeded
他要真把黄思思
in helping her,
给扶起来了
you should be aware of your status.
那你可得小心了
Hello, Directors.
两位总监好
Director Xu,
许总监
your express delivery.
你的快递
I fetched them for you.
我帮你拿过来了
It may be inconvenient for you.
我怕你现在不太方便
Thank you.
谢谢啊
Can't you even
你现在自己连
carry express deliveries?
快递都拿不了了
That's exaggerated.
那倒不至于
Hello,
二位
any date at dinner?
晚餐有约了吗
There is a new Mediterranean Restaurant
旁边新开了一家
next to the company.
地中海餐厅
Do you want to try with me?
下班一起打个卡去
No need.
不用啦
I have a date.
我有约了
You know?
你知道了吧
I'm still single.
我还单身呢
I see.
明白
I'll try my best.
我会努力的
Good figure!
身材不错
She looks pretty in the formal dress.
穿礼服的时候很妖娆
Look at her energy!
你看人家这干劲
If I'm competing for energy
我现在要是跟她
with her,
拼体力啊
I'm bound to lose.
肯定是赢不了了
I have a tip for you.
我给你支一招
Just say it.
说
Delegate power.
放权
I agree.
附议
Wise choice!
智慧
If she's hard-working,
她不是能干吗
let her work hard.
那就让她干
We should check out
也得看看她到底
if she has the ability!
多大能耐呀
Do you know the information
知道我打听出
I lately found out?
什么新情报了吗
Spill the tea!
快跟我扒一扒
Not long after she resigned,
她辞职之后的没几天啊
the key member of the project group
蓝海有一整条
all resigned
项目组的骨干
in Blue Ocean,
都辞职了
which is her own team
都是她在那会儿
before she resigned.
招的嫡系部队
Now,
现在
due to the lockout of the timeline,
项目线停摆了
Mr. Yu is trapped
于总正在那儿
in anxiety.
焦头烂额呢
But she came here
可是她来我们这儿
all by herself.
就一个人来的呀
Those people are becoming
那这些人要成为她的
her outsourcing team,
外包团队呢
which is more efficient than yours.
不比她用你的人好用啊
Marvelous!
厉害啊
She earned more than I do.
她在蓝海挣得比我多呀
A new broom
反正她新官上任
sweeps clean.
这三把火
Her room has been cleaned up.
肯定是烧起来了
Afterward,
再往后
we'll see how strong the support
就看这张总
from Mr. Zhang can be.
对她有多大的支持了
In my opinion,
所以我说呀
give her all the tasks
使劲给她派任务
to finish!
让她干
The more, the better!
往死里干
We'll see
咱也得看看
if she on earth
她到底有没有
has multi-tasking ability.
多线处理任务的能力
You're being mean to her!
你这有点不厚道了啊
I'm doing it for you.
我为谁呀
Let me tell you.
我告诉你啊
You must raise your head up!
必须给我支棱起来
Dad,
爸
it's the best
这个现在是最好的
recovery massage oil.
康复按摩油
It's not painful.
不疼 您别怕
No strange smell at all.
没有怪味 爸
Don't worry...
您这放
Are you using it as a snuff bottle?
这您拿它当鼻烟壶呢
Dad,
爸
good for you!
您可真行
I'll massage gently.
我轻点给您做
Gently.
我轻点
It's okay.
轻点
Don't worry, Mom.
放心 妈 我轻点
Is it a little painful?
是不是杀得慌
A little bit?
有点杀是吗
I'll apply it gently, Dad.
我轻轻的啊 爸
Right away.
马上就好
It's painful at first.
第一下杀
You're sweating.
汗都出来了
Sorry, Dad.
真对不住爸
I'll be gentle!
给我爹轻点
Mom, the rehabilitation training
妈 您这康复训练 这
is arranged
排得这个计划
too frequently.
密度太大了
An said
安安说了
it's the prime time to do the training.
说现在是恢复的黄金期
We can't wait!
那得抓紧练
Your dad said he'll help you
你爸说 练好了
look after the baby after recovery.
还要给你看孩子呢
Why do I need Dad
看啥呀 我还指着爸呢
to look after our kid?
给我们看孩子
As long as Dad
我爸只要身体
has a healthy body,
恢复得棒棒的啊
you can be our
您将来就给我们当
art director,
场外的艺术指导
guiding us
指导我们怎样
how to cultivate our kid
把孩子培养得像
as clever and pretty
心心这么优秀
as Xin!
这么漂亮
Dad.
爸
Not bad.
挺好的啊
He can move it.
还玩呢
Still painful?
疼吗
Comfortable now.
舒服哈
Dad, when you recover,
爸 等您好了啊
I'll take you and mom to travel
我就带着您跟妈去旅游
all around China
走遍祖国的山山水水
to enjoy beautiful sights.
看遍大好河山
Finally, I'll bring you to
最后再去您出生的
your birthplace,
大东北
the Northeast China
带着妈和您
which snows heavily in winter.
去那个大雪飘飘的雪乡
Dress mom up as Snow White,
把妈打扮成白雪公主
and take a wedding photo of you.
给您二位照一个婚纱照
Dad?
爸
Do you want to freeze us to death?
你想冻死我们呢
Are you happy?
开心啊
Mom.
妈
Lin, why are you here?
临临 你怎么回来了
I heard that Dad fell down.
听说我爸摔啦
What's the matter?
怎么回事
I... I failed to help him up.
我 我一下没扶稳
It's not a big deal.
就这么点小事
There's no need to visit us.
你看你们俩都往回跑
I can take good care of him.
我能照顾好他
I have to pay a visit,
那也得来看一眼哪
or Meng'an will be worried.
不然梦安不放心啊
Dad,
爸
training is important,
复健归复健
but be careful.
要小心啊
Okay.
行
It's okay.
没事
Is that true?
真的假的
I can't tell.
看不出来啊
Right.
就是
Good for Wendy!
可以啊 温蒂姐
The young man is handsome!
这小哥哥真帅
Yes, Wendy.
是啊 温蒂姐
The handsome is so warm!
这小帅哥还挺暖呢
Ms. Zhang,
张姐 张姐
is it true
温蒂姐的事
about Wendy?
真的假的呀
She's not naive.
可不简单呢
Didn't you see the description?
你没看上面写的
She has two kids,
她之前有两个孩子
divorced her husband
还出轨男医生
by cheating with a male doctor,
甩了前夫
and got a large amount of money.
分了一大笔钱
Photos don't lie.
有图有真相
I can't believe
真看不出来
Wendy would do that!
温蒂姐是那样的人
It also said
那上面还说
she collided with other agencies
她之前在地产公司
to short sale the company
勾结外面的机构
back there,
做空公司
and blackmailed a lot of money!
而且还讹了一大笔钱呢
Mr. Zhou must be careful.
那周总可得小心了
Wendy.
温蒂姐
Mr. Zhou wants you
周总让您
to his office.
去他办公室一趟
Got it.
我知道了
Search for the IP address
查一下网上的
on the Internet,
互联网地址信息
and find out who's behind it.
找出幕后主使
I'll trace the person to the end
敢欺负耀辉的人
who bullies the employee of Yaohui Co.
我一定要溯到底
I'll do it now.
我马上去办
Come here, Wendy.
来 温蒂
I'm sorry, Mr. Zhou,
对不起周总
for affecting our company
给公司
in such a bad manner.
造成这么不好的影响
Your reputation is hurt.
是你的名誉受到损失
Why do you apologize to me?
你为什么要向我道歉
You may be avenged
是你之前调查
due to the financial product
那个地产公司的
of the real estate company
金融产品
that you inspected.
被人报复了吧
Managers of that company
之前地产公司
talked to me
他们找我聊过
if I didn't publicize the report,
说如果不公开那份报告
they will give me a lot of money,
他们会给我一大笔钱
but I decided to
但后来我决定
publicize it.
还是公开了
I don't want those
我不想让那些
innocent people
无辜的百姓
to suffer the loss.
蒙受损失
The Deputy Director
后来那个副总
was fired because of that.
因为这件事情被开除了
I think he might be the one.
我想应该是他在搞鬼
You did it in the right way.
这事你做得对
I support you.
我支持你
But Wendy,
但是温蒂
you must be careful.
你也得当心
After all, you have two kids.
毕竟你还有两个孩子
You have a family to protect.
一定要保护好家庭
If you have any trouble,
有什么事情
talk to me in time.
要及时跟我讲
Has the lunatic
那个疯子不会
harassed you already?
已经骚扰你了吧
He was sent to the police station.
之前 送过派出所
The last plot failed,
他现在是一计不成
and another plot comes.
又生一计
Why didn't you tell me earlier?
你怎么不早告诉我呀
It's my personal business,
我觉得这是我的私事
so I didn't tell you.
所以没有告诉你
I never expected it could
但是我真的没有想到
bring such a big trouble
会给公司带来
to our company.
这么大的麻烦
This incident has no effect
这件事不会给耀辉
on Yaohui Co.
带来任何的影响
I just hope the effect on you
我只是希望把这件事
can be under control.
对你的影响降到最低
Don't worry.
放心吧
The incident won't affect me.
这件事情不会影响到我
Anyway,
再说
I have my back against the wall.
我也没有退路了
Don't worry, Wendy.
你放心 温蒂
In Yaohui Co.
在耀辉
I'm your strongest support.
我就是你最坚强的后盾
Don't take those rumors
你不用在意那些
into heart.
流言蜚语
I won't allow them
我不会让那些
to hurt you.
流言伤害到你
Thank you, Mr. Zhou.
谢谢周总
Let's go.
走
Where are we going?
去哪儿啊
Let's put the work aside.
大家停一下手里的工作
I have an announcement.
我宣布件事情
Our colleague, Chen Wanzhen,
我们的同事陈婉真
as the project leader,
作为项目负责人
successfully signed a contract with
成功地为公司签下了
Aiying, a mother-and-kid flagship brand.
母婴旗舰品牌 爱婴
I'll keep the promise I made.
那我要兑现我的承诺
From now on,
从今天起
Chen Wanzhen is promoted
陈婉真正式地从经理
into the Senior Manager,
升职为高级经理
in charge of all items
负责母婴赛道的
on the mother-and-kid track!
全品类项目
Let's congratulate Wendy!
让我们祝贺温蒂
Wendy,
温蒂
congratulations!
祝贺你
Mr. Zhou.
周总
Say something.
说几句
Actually, my achievement
其实我今天的成绩
is closely connected
和大家的帮助
with your help.
是分不开的
I also thank Mr. Zhou
我也要谢谢周总
for the trust and support.
对我的信任和支持
I'm willing to devote
以后我愿意为耀辉
all my power and energy
献出我全部的
to Yaohui Co.
力量和精力
Thank you all.
谢谢大家
Want a drink?
想喝吗
Yes.
想
That's right.
想喝就对了
Do you know why
知道你为什么
you are always demotivated?
每天都萎靡不振吗
You lack the soul of a laborer:
缺少打工人的灵魂
coffee.
咖啡
Director Huang,
黄总监
your dress looks awesome!
这身衣服可太好看了
I didn't wear it in the morning.
我上午都没见你穿呢
I just changed it.
刚换的
I changed my suit at noon.
抽空回家换了一套
I have a client this evening.
晚上约了客户
Your residence is so near!
你家离公司这么近啊
It was far,
本来不是
but I moved next door to the company,
入职新苗以后
after starting work.
我就搬到公司隔壁了
It's convenient to work overtime.
方便加班嘛
You work too hard!
你太拼了
It's so late now,
不是 你这么晚了
can you fall asleep
你喝这咖啡
after drinking coffee?
你睡得着吗
A perfect match with overwork.
加班标配
I should learn from you!
我得跟你学习
Learn from me?
你还说我
You're slimmer than me!
你比我标准
Well,
我那个
I practice yoga every week.
我每周都得去练瑜伽
Next time,
下次
let's practice yoga together!
下次一块儿去
Okay, you can use my card!
行行行 你用我卡
Okay!
好的
So pretty!
真好看
Do you think so?
好看吗
Yes, I want to buy one.
好看 我也要买
It's so good to be single.
单身真好
I'm also single!
老娘也单身
You lose, apparently.
很显然你输了呀
Why am I defeated?
我哪儿输了
Have you moved your home for work?
你为公司搬过家吗
No.
没有
Have you changed your suit
你见人的时候
before seeing a client?
换过衣服吗
I'll buy one after work.
我下班就去买
The same dress?
买她那款吗
As if the dress suits you.
说得好像你会买似的
My figure also looks great
我就是穿她那款
if I wear the same dress.
我这身材也是很好的
Okay, fine.
你好 你好 你好
Stop criticizing me.
别光说我
Look at yourself.
你看看你自己
What do you wear when you
你看人家见客户穿什么
see a client?
你穿什么
When she's married,
等她结了婚
with the old
过上上有老
and the young to look after,
下有小的日子
she might be shabbier than me!
保不齐混得还没我好呢
Good self-consistency.
你自洽成功
Have you ever heard of an idiom?
有一句词你听说过吗
What?
什么
A stick in my throat.
如鲠在喉
Gonna lose!
输喽
Tits up!
支棱起来
I told you the color suits you!
我就说这个颜色适合你
Really!
真的
Let me see.
我看看
It's pretty.
好好看
It matches your complexion.
显得气色真好
Director Xu.
许总监
Am I bothering you?
没打扰你们吧
No.
没有
Here's the thing.
是这样
I have
我呢
assigned the work
把内容中心的工作呢
of the main part.
分配了一下
Two Deputy Directors
两位副总监
are ready for work,
都已经就位了
who have their own
也应该有自己的
work and jurisdiction.
工作和管辖
This is my assignment plan.
我呢 划分了一下
After you finish reading it,
你们看完了之后
you can talk to me privately.
可以单独找我聊
With assignment
咱们有分工
and cooperation,
然后有合作
we can manage to promote
争取把内容中心的工作
our work!
推动起来
Okay?
好吧
Okay.
好
Yours.
美川的
Meichuan is not familiar
美川 对内容的部分
with the content.
还不是很了解
You are more capable,
你呢 有能力
so you can work more,
就多干一点
and teach her how to do it.
顺便也带带她
No problem, Director Xu.
没问题 许总监
I have a small present for you.
给你备了份小礼物
Don't.
别了
I feel under pressure
你们老送我礼物
if you keep doing it.
压力很大的
Thank you.
谢谢啊
Okay.
那行
I'll delegate my power to you.
我放权了啊
Come on!
你们加油干
Okay.
好的
How's Xin?
心心怎么样了
Have a fever again?
又发烧了
Alright.
那行
I'll pay a visit to Dad,
一会儿我去看一眼爸
and then visit her.
然后就过去看她
Why does she have a fever again?
怎么又发烧了
Director Xu,
许总监
I've finished reading my part,
我分管的内容看完了
and I want to talk to you.
想跟你聊聊
Now?
现在吗
Are you leaving?
你要下班吗
It's time to be off duty.
到点了
It'll only take you a few minutes.
我就耽误你几分钟时间
For today's tweet,
今日推文这个
I have a new idea.
我想做点新尝试
What's your idea?
想怎么尝试
Can I change today's tweet
我可以根据新的热点
according to the hotspot?
更换今天的推文吗
Is it possible?
今天不行吧
It will be uploaded at nine.
九点就要上线了
The time is so limited.
应该来不及了
It's possible.
来得及
Aren't you seeing a client?
你不是还要去见客户
It doesn't matter.
不耽误啊
We have to pursue
而且出了新的热点
the new hotspot!
咱们得追啊
Am I right?
你说是不是
We're not working for the press.
我们做的不是新闻
But hotspots can't be missed.
但我们得紧跟热点
Director Xu,
许总监
since you give me
你把这项任务
the task,
交给我管了
you should support me
那我有新的想法了
and delegate power
你得支持
when I get new ideas!
得放权啊
Fine.
好啊
I let you take charge of the duty
既然交给你做
because I trust you.
肯定还是相信你的
Okay.
好嘞
Wait for my action!
看我行动吧
Bye-bye.
拜拜
How intense the competition is!
我这是被卷了吗
Alright.
行了 老爷子
The treadmill is ready.
已经装好了
Let me
我呀
have a try first.
给你试一试啊
I'll teach you how to use it.
教你怎么用
See?
你看
There's a green button.
这上面有一个绿键
It starts when you press it.
一按就开始了
Press it.
按一下
See?
你看
The speed
速度
is slow.
缓缓的
Very cozy.
很舒服
That's how we do it.
就这么着就行了
Very easy.
表现得很轻松
Right?
对吧
You can speed it up.
然后 还可以加速
Ready?
加速了啊
Speed it up.
加速
It's too fast!
加速了
Don't!
别
Hurry up!
快快快 快快快
Help me press the pause button!
快快快 帮我按暂停
Press the pause!
你快帮我按个暂停
Where is it?
在哪儿啊
The red button!
停 红的
Press it!
按按按
The red one!
红的 红的
I'm doing it!
按着呢 按着呢
I can't hold on anymore!
快 我坚持不住啦
Which one?
哪个
Hurry up!
快快快
Stop!
停啊
Jesus! It's so frightening!
妈呀 太吓人了
I was hoaxed!
被骗了
I told him
我跟他说
to find me a walking machine,
买一个助步器就行了
but the salesman
那个销售
said it had all the functions.
非让我一步到位
See?
得
The price is tenfold higher.
八十变八百了
Well,
不是
Jing,
她大姑
refund the treadmill.
你赶紧把这给退了吧
I won't.
不退 不退 不退
Put it aside
你随便找个地方
somewhere.
先放起来
Perhaps,
兴许呀
in less than one year,
一年半载的
he can use it.
老爷子 能用上
What's going on?
这干吗呢
Why are you breathing heavily?
呼哧带喘的
Well,
那个
I bought a treadmill
我给老爷子
for your father.
买了个走步机
Is it useful?
能用吗
Not now.
现在用不上
It's a little bit fast.
有点快
It's okay.
这 没事
I'm glad you're back.
你都回来了
Okay, I...
那行 我
I'll go back
我赶紧回去
to cook for them.
给他们做饭
No need.
不用了
They must have eaten outside.
他俩肯定在外边吃了
I'll visit Xin
我一会儿还得
in a while.
去看趟心心
Let's eat some at home.
咱俩就在家对付一口吧
Yes, eat at home.
就是 你就在家吃吧
Okay.
行
If we can't use the treadmill,
这个方法不行
I have other ways.
还有呢
Wait.
等着啊
What?
还有
Let me fetch it to you.
来 我给你拿
Still more?
咱还有呢
I have something else.
还有呢
The treadmill
光忙乎那个
caught our attention,
走步机了
and I forgot this.
也忘了
Old man!
老爷子
My husband
我们家老欧阳
made up a prescription.
给你配了一副药
All good medicine.
全是好药
I'll let Lanxiang boil it.
让兰香给你熬了
Bitter medicine cures sickness.
你可别嫌苦 要吃
Good for health!
养生
If only Xin
心心啊
is as obedient
要是能像老爷子
as your husband did!
一样听话就好了
She wouldn't have suffered a lot.
她也不至于 这是不
An,
安安
go to the hospital to see
你一会儿到医院去看看
if she's okay.
什么情况
If possible,
要实在不行
don't let her breastfeed.
让她别喂奶了
I also have the intention.
我早就想去了
But she doesn't want to see me.
这不是她不想见我吗
Haowen also
刚才浩文
gave me a phone call,
也给我打电话了
saying she has a fever.
说发烧了 让我去一趟
Well, I have no choice
我一想那赶紧吧
but to go and comfort her.
人家台阶都给了
I'm ready for her scolding.
那赶快下呀
Exactly.
对 对
You're right.
对 对 对
Persuade her as much as you can.
你呀 去了好好劝劝她
I know
我知道
she doesn't want to breastfeed,
她不想喂奶 想断奶
but it's not healthy
但是你也不能
to do it abruptly.
说断就断吧
When the mammary gland
人家奶路
is working smoothly,
走得好好的
she suddenly
您啪
cut it off
给断了
to block the way,
它不通了
and she's doomed to have a fever!
这肯定就要发炎发烧嘛
If she wants to wean, take it slowly.
你想断奶 那得慢慢来
Right?
是吧
She can't be capricious.
不能由着自己的性子
I made up a prescription for her.
我呀 给她开了个方子
I'll let Lanxiang make it for her,
让兰香熬好了给送去了
and it will be fine.
那应该就没问题了
Take your hands off!
手拿开
Darling,
老婆
change the ice bandage?
换个冰袋吧
I think the ice bandage
我觉得那个冰袋
has been used for too long
时间都过了
and it may not be effective anymore.
可能没什么作用了
Darling?
老婆
Change it now!
你倒是换呀
Okay.
好嘞
I'll help you change it.
我给老婆换个冰袋
Stop hemming and hawing!
磨磨叽叽
Strip it off.
把这个揪下来
It's so warm.
冰袋都热了
Okay.
好嘞
Be careful.
轻点
Take care.
小心 小心
Okay.
好好好
My hair!
头发 头发 头发
I'll change a new one for you.
给老婆换个新的
Here you are.
来
Okay.
好嘞
Your weight is crushing me!
压死我了
Am I?
压上了
Do you feel better?
好点吗
I feel sick.
难受
Darling,
老婆
have a good rest.
好好躺着
I'll go to see someone.
我去忙一下
Mr. Jia, will you go to the company?
贾总 明天您去公司吗
No.
不去
If available,
您有空
go to the company for work.
你多往公司跑跑呗
During your absence,
您不在
many procedures
好多项目流程
can't be promoted.
都推不下去
Your long absence
您老不在
has incurred complaints.
都有人有意见了
What are the complaints?
有什么意见啊
Can't the others run the company?
公司缺我就转不动了
I'm just absent for two weeks,
我这刚出来十天半个月
and you keep complaining.
你就嘚不嘚 嘚不嘚的
What's the point?
有什么好嘚不的
Yesterday, you were absent
主要是昨天董事会
from the board.
您也不在
You're absent for three times.
都缺席三次了
All shareholders are complaining.
其他股东都有意见
Let me tell you.
我跟你说
Nothing in the company
公司发生什么事
values more than my family!
也没有我老婆孩子重要